Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/amentch (LinkedIn) www.alexment.ch (Personal)

Top Skills

Python
Data Analysis
SQL

Alex Mentch

Data Scientist at PADI

Orange County, California Area

Summary

An electrical engineer turned data scientist with experience in defense research and social media, I use data to define direction and solve problems. I develop a deep understanding of the problem areas I work in and enjoy building productive relationships with cross-functional partners to drive results. My tools and languages include Python, Presto, Hive, Excel, and Tableau.

Experience

PADI

Data Scientist December 2019 - Present (4 months)

Orange County, California Area

Facebook
Data Scientist
May 2014 - November 2019 (5 years 7 months)
Seattle, WA

I've worked on the Search and News Feed product teams as a key team member involved in influencing, supporting, and driving product changes.

- Work with many cross-functional partners including product management, engineering, UX research, and design
- Set team goals and drive roadmap to achieve those goals
- Design, set up, and evaluate A/B tests
- Evaluate ranking algorithms and features
- Run exploratory analysis to discover new opportunities
- Metric development and tracking, forecasting trends, and identifying levers to move metrics
- Build and maintain ETL pipelines and metric dashboards

MIT Lincoln Laboratory
Associate Technical Staff
January 2012 - August 2012 (8 months)

Group: Advanced Sensor Systems and Test Beds

Page 1 of 3

- Developed models and techniques to determine aim point of missile seeker through passive radar sensing.
- Helped plan tests and collect data for multiple offsite projects.

MIT Lincoln Laboratory

Summer Researcher

May 2011 - August 2011 (4 months)

Group: Ballistic Missile Defense Systems Integration

- Developed program to characterize quality of radar tracking through cluttered environments.
- Delivered analysis of current tracking techniques and framework for further testing.

NASA Ames Research Center

Summer Researcher

June 2010 - August 2010 (3 months)

Group: Prognostics Center of Excellence

- Developed control interface utilizing hardware PLC in Simulink for control of an electromechanical actuator testbed.
- Contributed to control scheme research attempting to compensate for crosscoupling between opposing actuators.

University of Idaho

Summer Researcher

June 2009 - August 2009 (3 months)

 Coded artificial neural network and genetic algorithm to generate adaptive walking gait for legged robot.

Camp MayMac

Head Counselor

June 2008 - August 2008 (3 months)

- Led 25 person staff and oversaw weekly groups of 60-80 campers.
- Set staff schedules, handled discipline issues, improved weekly events schedule, and was generally everywhere all the time.

Education

Washington University in St. Louis

B.S., M.S., Electrical Engineering (2007 - 2011)

Zipfian Academy

Data Science · (2014 - 2014)